

## PARVATHY VAZHOOR

#### WEB DEVELOPER

parvathyvd@gmail.com

**J** 604-358-3962

in linkedin.com/in/parvathy-vazhoor

♦ codepen.io/parvathyvd

github.com/parvathyvd

### **PORTFOLIO**

https://webfolio.realwordpressdevelopment.com/

### **EDUCATION**

Bachelors Degree in Computer Science
Vidya Academy of Science & Technology, India

#### **LANGUAGES**

English

Hindi

## OTHER INTERESTS

Biking

Glass Painting

Dancing

# **CONTACT ADDRESS**

8277 161st Surrey BC, V4N0N3

## CAREER PROFILE

I am a web developer specializing in Front end development. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for dynamic web projects. Well-versed in numerous programming languages including **HTML**, **CSS**, **Bootstrap**,

PHP(Codeigniter) and Vanila Javascript(Jquery,React). Strong background in Wordpress web development and design.

# **WORK HISTORY**

#### **FULLSTACK DEVELOPER (FREELANCER)**

REALWORDPRESSDEVELOPMENT (09/2020 to Present)

Developed web apps using HTML5, CSS3, BOOTSTRAP and Javascript(React).

Developed custom websites using Wordpress CMS.

Developed custom themes, Set up the stripe payment checkout using glass register for charity websites for Frontier (contract work).

#### **FULLSTACK DEVELOPER**

RSTINSTRUMENTS (09/2018 Sep to 09/2020)

Responsible for redeveloping the RST website.

Upgraded the HTML website to custom **PHP** website and **MYSQL** database with newer design. Designed and developed website using PHP, HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript ES6.

Migrated and redeveloped the entire website with same design in to the Wordpress.

### WEB DEVELOPER/DESIGNER

BRIKERS (05/2017 to 07/2018)

Developed Brikers website wireframe using Lucidchart.

Developed brikers website using Codeigniter(PHP framework), Bootstrap and jquery. Used SASS preprocessor.

Tested webpage for responsiveness and adjusted the media queries accordingly.

## WEB DEVELOPER/DESIGNER

ENGAGEMEDIA (07/2013 to 04/2017)

Responsible for all stages of Web site creations for client, from initial design and architecture to development, deployment, and management.

Developed websites mainly **Wordpress CMS**. Responsible for Domain registration, Webhosting, Wordpress, theme, plugin installation and customization.

Developed custom wordpress templates

## FULL STACK DEVELOPER

ABSOLUTE NATURAL PRODUCTS(Freelance 09/2016 to 10/2016)

Responsible for all stages of Web site development. Wordpress Web design/development, Social Media, SEO,

Business Card design and Office 365 email configuration.. Hosted the domain and installed the WordPress CMS.

Added necessary plugins and Customized the website.

# WEB DEVELOPER

BUSINESS ASSIST CANADA(Freelance 06/2014 to 11/2014)

Responsible for all stages of Web site development. Web design/development, Social Media, SEO, Graphic Card design and Office 365 email configuration.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**





Google Search Console
Google Tag Manager
Godaddy & Hostgator
Mailchimp
Filezila
VSC, Phpstorm, Atom, Coda2, Dreamweaver
MAMP



©copyright 2022 | All rights reserved | Designed by Parvathy Vazhoor